morrisons.co.uk 2019-04-03

# Privacy Policy | Morrisons

_Last updated: 12/06/2018_

Your privacy is extremely important to us so we want you to know exactly what kind of information we collect about you and how we use it. 

We've set out all the details below. 

Please take the time to read and understand this policy. 

To help you, we've included some links to other websites. It's worth remembering though that other people, not us, control these websites. We're not responsible for them. 

This notice has different sections which you can click through for further details of our privacy policy.

### About Us

We are **Wm Morrison Supermarkets Plc**. 

We are the 'data controller' of the information you provide us with, which means we control the way information is used and processed. 

### How we collect your personal information?

### Direct interactions

You may give us your Identity, Contact, Special Category and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you: 

  * apply for our More Card; 
  * pay  for goods and services; 
  * speak to or contact customer services; 
  * ordering our products or services; 
  * create an account on our websites; 
  * subscribe to our service or publications; 
  * request marketing to be sent to you; 
  * contact us through our call centre; 
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; 
  * give us some feedback; 
  * by filling in forms, for example when you sign up to offers, news or a competition; 
  * by sending us emails and text messages (SMS or MMS); 
  * by adding posts, reviews and other comments to any of our websites, mobile apps or other community forums; 
  * by liking or disliking our offers and promotions; 
  * by adding offers, promotions or products to your shopping lists on our Morrisons More mobile app; 
  * by interacting with us on social media platforms such as Facebook or Twitter etc; 
  * by talking to us in our stores, pharmacy or over the telephone. For example, when enquiring about a purchase, collecting a prescription or making a complaint; 
  * by registering accounts on any of our websites or mobile apps including setting up passwords and preferred user names, contact details, account details, details of friends and relatives, your preferences and interests; 
  * by using Morrisons partners and affiliated services.

### Automated technologies or interactions.

As you interact with our website(s), we may automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive technical data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy for further details. 

When you visit our estate we may video or photograph you by CCTV, camera or video equipment for security, promotion or marketing purposes. 

### Third parties or publicly available sources.

We may receive personal data about you from various third parties as set out below: 

  * Technical Data from the following parties: 
    * analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU; 
    * advertising networks; and 
    * search information providers.

  * Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Mastercard, Barclaycard, American Express, Experian based inside and outside of the EEA. 
  * Identity and Contact Data from data brokers or aggregators based inside the EEA.

### Your Personal Data

We may collect, store, and use the following categories of personal information about you: 

### Identity Data

Title, first name, last name, username or similar identifier, date of birth, Morrisons More card number and gender. 

### Contact Data

Billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers. 

### Financial Data

Bank account and payment card details. 

### Transaction Data

Details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us. These include: 

  * the time, date and location of purchase; 
  * the products and fuel you buy from us; 
  * any relevant delivery address; 
  * o  the resulting points and other benefits you accumulate through our Morrisons More card; 
  * any vouchers, coupons or other alternative means of payment you may use, as well as relevant payment cards such as a credit or debit card.

### Technical Data

  * Internet protocol (IP) address; 
  * MAC address; 
  * IMEI number from your phone; 
  * your login data; 
  * browser type and version; 
  * time zone setting and location; 
  * browser plug-in types and versions; 
  * device model; 
  * device name; 
  * operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website; 
  * information where you came to our site from, and where you went when you left it. 
  * information when you use our in-store WIFI networks to access the internet which includes the time and geographic location of your device when you do so; 
  * We also track how often you visit and use our websites and mobile apps. We do this via email and website cookies and similar tracking technology built into our mobile apps. We make cookie policies available on each of our websites to give you more detailed information on how we use them. The cookie policy for this website is set out [here](https://my.morrisons.com/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

### Profile Data

  * your username and password; 
  * purchases or orders made by you; 
  * your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses; 
  * CCTV, video and photographic footage, video and stills; 
  * car number plate; 
  * profile information and insight from organisations that already hold information on you, such as credit reference agencies and customer insight companies. This gives us their views on your household, your status, as well as your possible preferences and behaviours; 
  * likely makeup of your household (e.g. how many children you may have and their likely average age) and what your household affairs may be like, the type of car you may drive, your interests (including the kind of magazines and newspapers you may read, where you might go for your holidays and whether you're environmentally conscious or not) and where you're likely to shop. It also includes observations about your likely education and employment status, the type of job you may have and your likely financial status (including your mobile phone expenditure, what credit, debit and other cards you may hold, your current account status and any loans, investments and savings you may have). It also places you into one or more defined behavioural and socio-economic groups.

### Usage Data

  * Information about how you use our website, products and services; 
  * Information on what you view, click on access by way of our marketing emails and text messages (SMS, MMS), website and mobile.

### Marketing and Communications Data

Your preferences in receiving marketing from us, our third parties, and your communication preferences. 

### Aggregated Data (sometimes referred to a pseudonymised data)

We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data (sometimes referred to a pseudonymised data) such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice. 

### Special Category Data

We may also collect, store and use the following "special categories" of more sensitive personal information such as your racial or ethnic origin, religious beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature and your physical condition (e.g. if you're pregnant). We ask for a fair amount of this kind of detail in the forms you fill in, and you can choose whether or not you want to provide it. However, we may also acquire it through social media or as a result of our analysis of your preferences and behaviours. 

### How we will use information about you?

We will only use your personal information when the law allows us to. We will use your personal information in the following circumstances: 

  * When you consent to us doing so; 
  * Where we need to perform the contract we have entered into with you; 
  * Where we need to comply with a legal obligation; 
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

### Legitimate Interest

  * means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience; 
  * We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests; 
  * We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).

We may also use your personal information in the following situations, which are likely to be rare: 

  * Where we need to protect your interests (or someone else's interests); 
  * Where it is needed in the public interest or for official purposes.

### Purpose/ activity, type of data and lawful basis for processing

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. 

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please _contact us_ if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below. 

Some of the above grounds for processing will overlap and there may be several grounds which justify our use of your personal information. 

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---|---  
  
CCTV for Security and public safety 

| 

Profile Data and Special Category Data 

| 

Legitimate purpose for crime prevention and public safety   
  
Video and photographs for marketing and promotional purposes 

| 

Profile Data and Special Category Data 

| 

Legitimate Purpose for marketing and promotional purposes   
  
To register you as a new customer 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

| 

(a)    Performance of a contract with you 

(b)   Your consent 

(c)    Necessary for our legitimate interest to set up and manage your account   
  
To process and deliver your order including: 

(a) Manage payments, fees and charges 

(b) Collect and recover money owed to us 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Financial 

(d) Transaction 

(e) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a)    Performance of a contract with you 

(b)   Necessary for our legitimate interests (to fulfil your order or recover debts due to us)   
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy 

(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey 

(c) Responding to your queries and comments, social media posts and questions. 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Profile 

(d) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation 

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services) 

(d) Your consent   
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Profile 

(d) Usage 

(e) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)   
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Technical 

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation   
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Profile 

(d) Usage 

(e) Marketing and Communications 

(f) Technical 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
  
To use data analytics gathered from our website, mobile apps and in-store WIFI networks to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences 

| 

(a) Technical 

(b) Usage 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you 

| 

(a) Identity 

(b) Contact 

(c) Technical 

(d) Usage 

(e) Profile 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)   
  
To provide you with our mobile apps and in-store WIFI networks 

| 

(a)    Identity 

(b)   Technical   

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests. It also lets us do things such as recognise your username and password, as well as reset them if you happen to forget what they are.   
  
To power our security measures and services in order to protect you and our business 

| 

(a)    Identity 

(b)   Technical 

(c)    Usage 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interest so you can safely access our website and mobile apps. It also lets us do things such as recognise your username and password, as well as reset them if you happen to forget what they are.   
  
To deliver NHS Pharmacy Services – For example dispensary of NHS Prescriptions, medicine reviews, support/ referral services including diabetes and blood pressure checks. 

| 

(a)    Identity 

(b)   Special Category 

(c)    Contact 

(d)   Financial 

(e)   Transaction 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation 

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests 

(d) Your consent   
  
### Marketing

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. 

**Promotional offers from us**

If you have expressly opted-in to receive marketing from us we may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). 

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing. 

**Third-party marketing**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the Morrisons group of companies for marketing purposes. 

**Opting out**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time through our website or by [ _contacting us_ ](https://my.morrisons.com/help "Contact Us") at any time. 

**Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please click [here](https://my.morrisons.com/cookie-policy/). 

**Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal information for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. 

If we need to use your personal information for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so. 

Please note that we may process your personal information without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law. 

### Disclosure of Personal Data

On occasion we may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out. 

### Internal Third Parties

Companies, brands and businesses within our group. For example, we’ll share information from our online food business with Morrisons.com and there are similar arrangements between our other online and store-based businesses. This is because we hope to have a relationship with you across all our different brands and businesses, if not now, then sometime in the future and we want to be able to provide you with the same value-for-money, high quality experience whenever and however you shop with us. It’s also the only way we can provide you with the full benefits of our Morrisons More card. 

### External Third Parties

  * **Service providers:  **acting as processors based within the EEA who provide IT and system administration services.

  * **Professional advisers:  **acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based within the EEA who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and professional service providers.

  * **HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities: **acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances. 

  * **Other people who help us provide our websites, mobile apps, in-store WIFI networks, stores, Morrisons More card and related services to you:**  They include information technology experts who design and host our websites, and payment services companies that make it easy for you to use your credit or payment cards with us. Other examples include market research companies, marketing, advertising, design and PR organisations and general service companies such as printers, mailing houses and form-scanning service providers.

  * **Our insurers and insurance brokers:**  who provide us with comprehensive cover against the risks of running a business as big as ours. (They may keep this information for the purpose of ongoing risk assessment and insurance broking and underwriting services.)

  * **Banks and finance companies:  **where we have allowed them to offer you the possibility of buying our products on credit or with a loan arranged through our stores or online. (They may keep this information for their related banking and finance purposes)

  * **Credit reference agencies:**  who supply anti-fraud and credit-insight information to us, central and local government departments such as the Driver Vehicle Licence Agency (DVLA) and local authorities who run the UK electoral rolls, banks and finance companies that also provide anti-fraud services, and customer insight companies. Where anti-fraud is concerned, the organisations concerned may hold your information on file for future anti-fraud-prevention purposes.

  * **Third-party companies:**  whose products and services we sell, so they can better understand the profile of our customers who buy from or are interested in them. However, all the information we share will be collected and anonymised, so neither you nor any of your devices can be identified from it.

  * **With social media companies such as Facebook and Twitter:  **and our advertising partners to enable us to run targeted promotions for you on their platforms;

  * **Rewards companies:**  which you have signed up to, in order for you to receive the rewards and benefits they offer when you shop with us. (They may keep this information)

  * **Any new business partners:  **we may have over time, for example, in the event of a joint venture, reorganisation, business merger or sale that affects us.

  * **The Police, local authorities, Her Majesty’s Revenue and Customs (HMRC), the courts and any other government authority:  **if they ask us to do so (but only if us doing so is lawful).

  * **Other people who make a ‘subject access request':**  where we are required to do so by law. 

  * **We may also share the information we collect where we are legally obliged to do so, e.g. to comply with a court order.**

  * **Social media, blogs, reviews, etc.**

  * **Any social media posts or comments you send to us:  **(on the Morrisons Facebook page, for instance) will be shared under the terms of the relevant social media platform (e.g. Facebook or Twitter) on which they’re written, and could be made public. Other people, not us, control these platforms. We’re not responsible for this kind of sharing. Before you make any remarks or observations about anything, you should review the terms and conditions and privacy policies of the social media platforms you use. That way, you’ll understand how they will use your information, what information relating to you they will place in the public domain, and how you can stop them from doing so if you’re unhappy about it. It’s worth remembering too that any blog, review or other posts or comments you make about us, our products and services on any of our blogs, reviews or user community services will be shared with all other members of that service and the public at large. You should take extra care to ensure that any comments you make on these services, and on social media in general are fit to be read by the public, and are not offensive, insulting or defamatory. Ultimately, you are responsible for ensuring that any comments you make comply with any relevant policy on acceptable use of those services. 

  * **Mobile app platforms** **:  **Our mobile apps run on third party software platforms, for example, Apple’s iOS platform, which powers Apple’s iPhone, and Google’s Android platform, which powers Android-based smartphones. If you use **any of our mobile apps** , your usage of those apps is also subject to the relevant mobile app platform provider’s terms and conditions and privacy policy. You should review their terms and conditions and privacy policy to ensure you understand what information (if any) they will gather on you, how they will use that information, and what you may be able to do if you are unhappy about it.

  * **Morrisons Flowerworld, Nutmeg and Food to Order Payments** **:**  When using the Morrisons Flowerworld and Food to Order services we use a different payment processor to that used for processing orders from the Morrisons Groceries site. Payments for the Morrisons Flowerworld services are processed through a payment processing company called Stripe, and payment for the Food to Order service are processed through Barclays Bank plc trading as Barclaycard. Stripe and Barclaycard will process your credit or debit card data. This data is handled according to Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS) compliant rules and processes.  We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order.  We securely transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing. All direct payment gateways adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover.

  * **Third parties:**  to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice. We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law.  We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### International Transfers

We share your personal data within the Morrisons Group. This may involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ). 

Some of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA. 

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented: 

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.

  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.

  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may securely transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.

 Please contact us if you want further information on how we transfer your personal data out of the EEA. 

### Data Security

A lot of the information we receive reaches us electronically, originating from your devices, and is then transmitted by your relevant telecoms network provider. 

Where it's within our control, we put measures in place to ensure this 'in flight' data is as secure as it possibly can be. 

Once it arrives at Morrisons, you can be sure we take the security of your information very seriously. 

We use appropriate procedures and technical security measures (including strict encryption, anonymisation and archiving techniques) to safeguard your information across all our computer systems, networks, websites, mobile apps, offices and stores. 

In particular, we follow the internationally recognised security standard including the Payment Card Industry's Data Security standards (PCI-DSS). 

We use secure means to communicate with you where appropriate, such as 'https' and other security and encryption protocols. 

If you have any concerns about the security of your own personal computers and mobile devices, we suggest you read the advice of ‘Get Safe Online’, which can be accessed [here](https://www.getsafeonline.org/). 

### How long do we keep your information for?

To make sure we meet our legal data protection and privacy obligations, we only hold on to your information for as long as we actually need it for the purposes we acquired it for in the first place. 

In most cases, this means we will keep your information for as long as you continue to shop with us or use our services, and for a period of time afterwards if you stop doing so just in case you begin shopping with us again. 

After that we will either delete it or anonymise it so that it cannot be linked back to you. 

Please note that for our Morrisons More mobile app, in order to be able to provide you with the best and most appropriate offers, promotions, product information and content, we need to build up a profile of what you like and dislike and what you may have previously been interested in. As part of this, we retain all data that you choose to delete from the app (such as a previous shopping list) for a limited time. We use it to compare your deleted data with the data you currently store so that we can work out what you are no longer interested in. By doing so we help ensure that the app content and the offers and promotions we show you are as relevant to you as possible. We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, for example for any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. 

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes. 

 In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see _Request erasure_ below for further information. 

 In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

### Rights of access, correction, erasure, and restriction

### Your duty to inform us of changes

It is important that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal information changes by keeping your details up to date on your More Card and online shopping accounts. 

### Your rights in connection with personal information

Under certain circumstances, by law you have the right to: 

  * **Request access:**  To your personal information (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

    * **No fee usually required:  **You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

    * **What we may need from you:  **We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

    * **Time limit to respond:  **We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

  * **Request access:**  Of the personal information that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate information we hold about you corrected. We may need to verify the accuracy of any new data you provide to us.

  * **Request erasure:**  Of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal information where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

  * **Object to processing:**  Of your personal information where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal information for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which means we can continue to process your personal information.

  * **Request the restriction of processing:**  Of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: 
    * (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; 
    * (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; 
    * (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or 
    * (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 

  * **Request the transfer:**  Of your personal information to another party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. 

  * **Right to withdraw consent at any time:  **Where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

### Fees for excessive or unreasonable requests

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal information (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request for access is unfounded or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with the request in such circumstances. 

### What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is another appropriate security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. 

### Data Protection Officer

The Morrisons Data Protection Officer (DPO) oversees compliance with this privacy notice. If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Notice or how we handle your personal information, please contact the DPO at [dataprotection@morrisonsplc.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@morrisonsplc.co.uk). You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO) <https://ico.org.uk/>, the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy at any time, and we will provide you with a new Privacy Policy when we make any substantial updates. We may also notify you in other ways from time to time about the processing of your personal information. ** **

**If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact the Data Protection Officer** [ **dataprotection@morrisonsplc.co.uk** ](mailto:dataprotection@morrisonsplc.co.uk) **.**

Top
